David Andrew Dronsfield

52 Pearce Manor, Chelmsford, Essex, United Kingdom. CM2 9XH

d.a.dronsfield@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/DavidDronsfield

07599199429

Personal Profile

An enthusiastic and imaginative web developer, I am able to work alongside other talented IT professionals to create websites to the very highest standards. I have a high awareness of new innovations such as Sass and Bootstrap, fluid grids and responsive design, as well as best practice within these fields. I am self-taught, possess genuine enthusiasm and eager to learn and grow as a developer within a committed team and the wider web development community. I am looking for an entry-level position with an exciting company that wants to attract driven people, who love what they do.

Since graduating with a law degree I have worked for three years as a Quality Assurance Advisor, developing my administrative, leadership and interpersonal skills, and proving myself to be self-motivated, organised, meticulous, and capable of consistently meeting the highest expectations on time and under pressure.

I have a clear, logical mind with a freethinking approach to problem solving and a drive to see projects through to completion. I enjoy working on my own initiative or in a team. In short, I am hardworking, conscientious and looking for new commitments and challenges.

Skills

- Object-oriented programming
- Git
- HTML5
- · CSS3
- Sass
- Javascript

- iQuery
- SQL
- CSS Animations
- Responsive design
- Aware of international web standards and protocols

Qualities

- Research skills, drawing from a range of sources including verbal questioning and listening.
- Evaluation skills both statistical and logical, including familiarity with interpreting, presenting and explaining complex data succinctly.
- The ability to formulate sound and considered arguments.
- Flexibility, dedication, rapid learning and lateral thinking.
- The ability to deliver results under intense pressure and as part of a team.
- Concern for detail, and the ability to understand and draft formal documents with clarity and coherence.
- Organisation, proactivity, self-discipline and perseverance.
- Microsoft Office Suite proficiency, literacy and numeracy.
- I find professional satisfaction in delivering results above and beyond my job description.

Qualifications

2006- 2010: University Education

University of Kent Law School, Canterbury, Kent.

LLB (Hons) Law

1997-2005: Secondary Education

Hylands School, Chelmsford, Essex.

A Level in Biology: (B)

Boswells School, Chelmsford, Essex.

A Levels in Economics and Business Studies: (A)

English Literature: (A)

History: (A)

General Studies: (A)

Hylands School, Chelmsford, Essex.

11 GCSEs: 1 A*, 6As, 4Bs

Employment History

2012- Present: Quality Assurance Advisor, VCG Kestrel, Witham

- This is my current role, which involves ensuring that packaging ranges contain the correct information, are consistently branded, and conform to specific technical print criteria by collating information from several sources including an IT system.
- It requires consistent precision and disciplined self-management in a high pressure and deadline-driven environment.
- Liaising with a busy team in Australia means excellent communication skills via telephone and email, tact, organisation and close teamwork are the key to unfailingly meeting targets.
- Measured output volume in the last six months averaged over twice the company average.

2005- 2006: Office Administrator, Chapter Two, London

- This role involved networking with local community leaders, organisation of a warehouse, cataloguing an archive of historic publications, retail experience and the preparation of formal documents.
- I provided clerical and organisational support as a member of a team, and built ongoing customer relationships.
- It also involved taking notes in board meetings, preparing formal letters from dictation, administrative support for senior management and submitting reports on a variety of subjects.

Summer 2005: Warehouse Manager, DP Furniture, Maidstone

 This role required excellent problem solving skills, necessitating efficiency and preplanning to ensure the smooth running of a busy furniture warehouse, with a high volumes of stock moving in and out of a very limited space.

Interests and Activities

I enjoy outdoor activities, such as cycling and hiking. I also enjoy learning to speak
Tagalog, reading, playing badminton and travel.

References	are	availa	able o	n req	uest.